Murdered Mind If thoughts could kill, a
mind would run as red as Cain, With fill
of all that has been fought, 'til
blindness spreads a final stain.
It penetrates the waking hours, a darkness
lost and so alone, And violates all sense
of peace by smothering a peace once
known.
The mind is filled with countenance
relating to a mental slaughter, Until an
effort wills the thoughts to turn from
blood and flow like water.
Their purity is self-contained, a
self-sincere and fragile lie; There is no
cure that can be gained once the true
self decides to die.
Then deep within what was deemed right
will warp and twist like isometal,
Unleashing darkness in the light without
a chance to clearly settle.
No foresight could achieve a vision,
accurate, composed, or sane, Of
infliction from decision, or the
encumbrance of the pain.
So find this state of mind confined and
try to kill it if you can; You'll only
see what was designed, and be filled with
how it all began.
A warping was the end that's sought;
inside this head, the lies were spread,
Now wound so tight with mischief wrought,
a dormant pain plots for the dead.
No one will ever hear the screams from
muffled souls in their desire, They'll
manifest as tortured dreams, like sighs
from a heart set on fire.
But what's left when the thrashing ceases
and baneful battle has allayed?
Perhaps the theft of inner peace has
tarnished soul and beast unmade.
Once supernal dust has cleared, a
whispered thought born from the embers,
The brain is blind to what it feared, and
how the brutal end dismembers.
A truth was told that this fierce soul
could not and would not be controlled, A
truth that loves the flat, cold rues from
words that never could extol.
The actuation of its strength lies in a
faithful, grim design: To bring a famine
to a soul, a final, starving anodyne.
The deepest pain lies in the core of how
this bitter conflict grew: That one moved
on and closed the door, to leave a life
for hot pursuit… Of someone else, who
broke the chain of all the love that had
been found, So left here, wounded in the
brain, it tries to wound me void of
sound.